

Sajeev Dharan

Dubai +971 56 92 94 194
UAE s_dharan@hotmail.com

ABOUT ME

Passionate Hotelier, capable of leading Great Hotels with Great people, earning Return on investment, and Guest Satisfaction. Being an allrounder led by live examples, inspiring the team to achieve the desired result.

21 years of Hospitality expertise, working with 6 International Hotel Brands, 12 Hotels across multiple brands in 5 cities & multiple countries.

SKILLS & PROFICIENCIES

- People Management & Development Skills
- Controlled expenses for better GOP %
- Topline overall revenue growth strategies
- · In-depth departmental working knowledge
- Social Media Marketing skills
- · Guest satisfaction / Reputation management
- Preopening projects with chain hotels
- · Rebranding / Refurbishing projects
- · Hotels Channel Management & distribution network.
- · Multiple awards for Quality & Safety audits
- Consistent budget and KPI achievements

CERTIFICATION & VOLUNTEER WORK

Stay Real

Guest Experience 2009 - IHG Jeddah, Saudi Arabia Collaborated with 2 hotels team trained total of 320 team members and HOD's

Being Brand hearted

Guest Experience &GM training 2012 - IHG Al Barsha, Dubai Collaborated with 4 hotels team, trained over 500+ team members and HOD's.

Rates & Rate codes - IHG Revenue academy
Holidex plus - Hands-on - IHG Revenue academy
Covid Care Community health support
Covid Prevention voluntary member
Guest speaker for Laurels institute - Dubai.
(For Hospitality Fraternity, Dubai & Abu Dhabi)

WORK HISTORY

Hilton International - 2001 - 2005 - 5 * - AFOM (21 Acres, 180 rooms and suites, 8 outlets, 10 Floor SPA, Banquet halls, Sports Block, 150-meter Swimming pool). Bangalore.

Sarovar Premiere Hotel - 2005 - 2007 - 5* -FOM/RDM (Hilton garden inn),140 rooms and suites, 6 outlets, SPA, Banquet halls, Swimming pool) Thiruvananthapuram

Intercontinental Hotels & Resorts Group - 2007-2013 - 5* -RDM Holiday Inn Sharjah & Dubai (Pre-opening)200 Rooms, 4 F&B outlets, Banquet hall -400 & 150 pax, Spa, Health club. Holiday Inn Express Dubai Cluster (Re-branding) 3*

Millennium & Copthorne Hotel - 2013 - 2018 - 4* - Rooms Manager 255 rooms and suites, 4 F&B outlets, Spa floor, health club, banquet hall, meeting rooms. Sharjah Premium Al Majaz water front

Louvre Hotels Group - Royal Tulip - 2019 - 2021 - Cluster Operation Manager

Royal Tulip Act Hotel - 150 Rooms, 4 meeting rooms, 4 f&B outlets, 1Spa, health club facilities, Banquet operations - 5*

Royal Tulip 72 Hotel - 72 Rooms, 4 meeting rooms, 4 f&B outlets, 1Spa, health club facilities. - 5*

Regent Palace Hotel Dubai - 4* - Hotel Manager, Bur Dubai-150 rooms, 7 outlets including a sports bar, nightclubs, lounges and restaurant, 2 spas, meeting rooms.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Nagpur University

Post Graduation in Travel & Tourism Administration, 1999-2000 with rank in University

University of Kerala

Bachelor's Degree in Economics and Statistics 1993 -1996

Digital Magnet

Digital Marketing for Hospitality 2021

Sajeev Dharan

Al Fahidi Street, Dubai - UAE

+971-56-92-94-194 s_dharan@hotmail.com

Hospitality Management / Multi-Property Operation Exposure;

- 20+ years of Hospitality Experience in the Middle East Market
- · Served as Hotel manager for multi-unit operations
- · Project Manager for renovation, Pre-opening, and other Capex projects
- Hotels Quality Audit and classification Audit by Authorities Brands
- Improved Hotel Reputation for the hotel/s by 4 to 7 points
- Constantly achieving the targeted Budget revenue and GOP %
- KPI performance across the board utilizing the tools effectively
- Providing visible leadership across all levels of operations
- Best Practices on Revenue Management and guest experience touchpoints
- Regular property updates and Preventive / Maintenance
- Compliance with operating guidelines of brand and Legal entities
- · Consistent review of operational cost and control expenses, operating costs, etc.
- Practicing Energy/water conservation and recycle
- · Achievement of Three Quality Excellence Awards, Green Hotel Award

Revenue Management & Ecommerce

- Consistent review of Budget/Forecast to bridge the gaps
- · Driving Revenue culture across the departments and manage change
- Supply control on manpower best-matching Payroll expenses without anticipation of the guest experience.
- · Keep monitoring the market trends and reviewing the purchases and AMC's
- Driving the top-line revenue through various segment promotions and pricing.
- · Monitoring the market trends, Events, socioeconomic factors, regional political scenario, etc.
- Ensuring media plan is available and active across rooms, F&B, Spa, and marketing team.
- Ensuring the hotel content marketing is actively done

Room Division & Guest Experience Management:

- Improved guest satisfaction through personalized experiences
- Coaching, training, and development improving guest communication
- Distinguished Welcome, Pre-Arrival, Arrival & Departure Experience to every guest
- FO upselling, Loyalty guest programs, and bookers programs are in place and effective
- Accuracy & effectiveness of guest data across various hotel departments
- Guest satisfaction and Survey reviews and guest conversion are in place.

Sales & Marketing:

- Customized Contracts and rates to all suppliers
- · Ensuring Selling strategy, Event planners across outlets are implemented
- Ensuring best use of Social Media and Electronic platforms generating leads or awareness
- Regular S&M review and create strategies to eradicate variances if any
- Visit competitions, Trade fairs, associates, affiliates, and clients, maintain PRO

Food & Beverage

- Sales strategy & Media planner available in all outlets
- Food & Beverage excel in Taste, Quality and in Presentation across the competition
- Selling strategy, setting Out let wise KPI, F&B cost management, and implementation of best practices
- Events P&L Year on year comparison for progress on all outlets/events & functions
- Ensuring the employee availability, guest interaction, up-selling policies, product knowledge matches SOP.
- Analyzing Timely outlet promotions and marketing efficiency aligned to the marketing Budget.

Human Resources, Training

- Practical Manning and Training Budget, HR activities, Team Building as per the annual calendar
- Employee, hiring, training, and performance appraisal is aligned to Brand/hotel strategies.

Respectfully yours,

